Drew Johnson

 $404-825-2866 \mid DrewJohnsonGT@gmail.com \mid linkedin.com/in/drewjohnsongt \mid github.com/drewjohnsongt \mid drewj.dev$

Accomplished Senior Software Engineer and Team Lead with over 8 years of experience specializing in full-stack development, cloud architecture, and big data solutions. Proven leadership in guiding teams of 5-8 engineers through the full product lifecycle at a high-growth unicorn cybersecurity startup. Experience in building, upgrading, and maintaining systems at the scale of Fortune 100/500 companies. Lifelong learner, always building something.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: TypeScript/JavaScript, Python, Scala, Java, GraphQL, SQL, Terraform, HTML/CSS

Frameworks/Tools: React, Node.js, AWS, GCP, Azure, Docker, Spark, Databricks, Tailwind CSS, Shadon/UI

Skills: Cloud Native Development, Full Stack Development, IaC, CI/CD and DevOps, data engineering

EXPERIENCE

Staff Software Engineer

Jul 2024 – Present

Log10

San Francisco, CA (Remote)

- **Technical Leadership**: Led application development at seed-stage AI startup, as the primary engineer responsible for frontend architecture, API design, and deployment strategies, supporting rapid product iterations and pivots.
- Full Stack Development: Migrated Next.js-based REST API to robust, end-to-end typesafe GraphQL architecture, improving developer productivity and cutting feature implementation time by 50%.
- Greenfield Product Development: Spearheaded development of a new HIPAA and SOC II compliant AI-driven document builder, including Terraform-based AWS deployment, GraphQL APIs, and gRPC integration.

Team Lead and Senior Software Engineer

Feb 2021 - Jul 2024

Raleigh, NC (Remote)

- JupiterOne
- Project Leadership: Led both technical and non-technical aspects of a teams of up to 8 engineers, translating ambiguous requirements into technical system designs and actionable implementation plans.
- Full Stack System Design: Drove SaaS architecture and development to support 1000%+ company growth, using React single-SPA microfrontends and serverless, multi-tenant, and asynchronous/event-driven AWS patterns.
- Big Data Engineering: Designed and implemented a high-throughput (25B records/hour) deduplication ETL system using Spark/Scala/Databricks, which consolidates CDC Delta Lake data, securing 1m+ ARR deal.
- AI/LLM: Championed the integration of AI and LLMs into the JupiterOne platform, leading the development of a feature that transforms natural language queries into a cipher-based DSL, increasing user engagement by over 400%.

Senior Software Engineer

May 2020 - Feb 2021

The Home Depot

Atlanta, GA (Remote)

- Full Stack Typescript: Authored suite of new React frontends and Node/Express/TypeORM layered multi-tenant microservice APIs for B2B/B2C tax exemption software, decreasing monthly legacy system requests by 2 million.
- Cloud Architecture and SRE: Directed GCP cloud architecture, CI/CD, and database migrations from legacy on-premise systems to new microservice architecture maintaining 99.99% uptime for 250k+ requests a day.

Senior Software Engineer

Sep 2019 – May 2020

Delta Air Lines

Atlanta, GA

- Cloud Architecture: Guided development architecture of Delta's first AWS cloud project, implementing real-time, high throughput data streaming from on-premise sources for the daily distributed processing of millions of records.
- Data Ingestion and Streaming: Integrated with hundreds of disparate legacy on-premise and cloud applications for real-time customer data ingestion, standardization, and consolidation around centralized IDs (SVOC).

Full Stack Software Engineer (Side contract)

 ${\rm Oct}\ 2018 - {\rm Sep}\ 2019$

 $Schenck\ Process$

Kansas City, MO

• Full Stack App Design/Development: Architected, developed, and implemented engineering product specification/sizing tool, saving hundreds of monthly engineer hours and preventing company liability issues.

Software Engineer

Oct 2017 – Sep 2019

Meridian Business Services

Overland Park, KS

• **Development Lead**: Led development efforts supporting company's 2-year 500% growth, establishing and maintaining core engineering best practices while delivering effective and efficient code.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA